A Guide to Herbert Gold Letters to Robie Macauley, 1969-1979
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Herbert Gold Letters to Robie Macauley, 1969-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8517-a
13 items
The collection consists of 13 letters, 1969-1979, from American author Herbert Gold to Robie Macauley.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Library purchased these items from Bev Chaney Jr. Books, on August 30, 1988.
Scope and Content Information
In a series of letters, 1969-1979, Gold writes to Robie Macauley about his books; the possibility of Macauley speaking to the Squaw Valley Community of Writers; his work with Unesco; his "addiction" to magazine writing; Anatole Broyard's review, and a movie version of, "Waiting for Cordelia"; and the "Herbert Gold Day" sponsored by the San Francisco Historical Society and Library.
Arrangement
Arranged by date.
Contents List
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1969 Nov 1, TLS; 1 p.
  Discusses his progress with his novel The Great American Jackpot to be published in late January.
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1970 Oct 5, TLS; 1 p.
  Apologizes for trying to "lean" on Macauley in his last letter and informs him that he isn't including "Zoya" in the collection of stories [ The Magic Will: Stories and Essays of a Decade?] because it may be the germ of a novel and it doesn't lit the book's American theme.
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1974 Jun 26, TLS; 1 p.
  Writes how pleased he was to have lunch with Macauley and encloses the story "Paternity" with its new pages and changes.
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1974 Jun 27, TLS; 1 p.
  Tries to entice Macauley into a visit to the isolated writers of the West by offering him an opportunity to meet Western writers, the possibility of speaking at the Squaw Valley Community of Writers, and fun.
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1974 Jul 7, TLS; 1 p.
  Discusses Macauley's arrangements with Blair Fuller for his upcoming visit to the Squaw Valley Community of Writers in San Francisco.
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1974 Jul 19, TLS; 1 p.
  Welcomes Macauley to stay at his condominium in Squaw Valley and expresses pleasure that Playboy can use his story "Paternity."
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1974 Sep 16, TLS; 1 p.
  Gold writes of his being honored on October 25 by the San Francisco Historical Society and the Library with a "Herbert Gold Day," and about his story "Lady Spain." He also says that his next publication will probably be a collection of stories about the varieties of love in San Francisco, tentatively entitled "Tales of San Francisco."
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1974 Nov 7, TLS; 1 p.
  Expresses his regret at missing Macauley's visit due to his teaching duties at the University of California, Davis.
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1976 Sep 26, TLS; 1 p.
  Writes of family news and is glad that Macauley liked his story "Stages;" an "extrapolation of what would have happened if I had gotten deeply involved with that lovely lady Kathy...Stories are sometimes, for me at least, warnings, putting the future into the past."
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1976 Nov 4, TLS; 1 p.
  Talks of his personal life since his divorce from Melissa, mentions his Paris trip to the International Symposium on behalf of UNESCO, and speaks of his prospective movie, Waiting for Cordelia.
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1977 May 23, TLS; 1 p.
  Discusses Anatole Broyard's review of Waiting for Cordelia.
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1978 Feb 3, TLS; 1 p.
  Mentions that Playboy rejected his story "Stages" because it did not fit its new format.
- Herbert Gold Letter to Robie Macauley 1979 Oct 31, TLS; 1 p.
  Describes his current magazine writing, "Magazine writing is a foolish addiction for me, like cigarettes for others," and mentions having just written an anguished novel [ Slave Trade?.